The three types you've seen so far are interster and float, turns out you can
Tri vrste koje ste do sada vidjelu su int, str i float. Ispostavlja se da ih možete
convert between them as follows. I'm going to take the number three and I'm
međusobno konvertovati kako slijedi. Uzeću broj tri i
going to call something called sturd, that gives me back a string of length one
pozvati nešto što se zove str. To mi vraća string dužine jedan
contained in the letter three, I can assign this to a variable.
koji sadrži znak tri. Ovo mogu dodijeliti varijabli.
Three is the string contained in the letter three.
To je string koji sadrži znak tri.
Since it's a string, I can multiply it by whatever I like.
Pošto je to string, mogu ga pomnožiti sa čime god želim.
Let's make 77 3's, just for the fun of it. As you might guess, I can go the other
Napravimo 77 3-ca, samo radi zabave. Kao što možete pretpostaviti, mogu ići i u drugom
direction. If I have five copies of this string
smjeru. Ako imam pet kopija ovog stringa
three. In other words, a string of link five
three, drugim riječima, string dužine pet
containing five letter 3's. Then, I can take that and I can turn it
koji sadrži pet znakova 3, onda ga mogu pretvoriti
into an int. There we go, 33,333.
u int. I evo, 33.333.
I can even use the result of that and convert it back to a string.
Čak mogu iskoristiti rezultat toga i pretvoriti ga ponovo u string.
Giving me what I would have gotten if I had just multiplied three by five.
Što mi daje isto što bih dobio da sam samo pomnožio varijablu three sa pet.
I can also convert floats to strings. If I use INT on a string containing
Također mogu konvertovati float u string. Ako koristim int na stringu koji sadrži
several digits, then I can get back that integer by extracting that value from the
nekoliko cifara, onda mogu povratiti taj integer izdvajanjem vrijednosti iz
string. I can also.
stringa. Također mogu
Do the same thing with a float. Notice that I gave float a string
uraditi isto i sa floatom. Obratite pažnju da sam floatu dao niz
containing letters that form an int and it turned that into a floating point number.
znakova koji formiraju int, a što je pretvorilo taj niz u broj sa pokretnim zarezom.
I have to be a little bit careful if I call int on a string that has things other
Moram biti malo pažljiv. Ako pozivam int na string koji sadrži znakove
than digits in it, I'm actually going to get an error.
osim cifara, dobiću zapravo grešku.
Here, forever all I'm going to get is a value ever, invalid literal for int with
U ovom slučaju, grešku koju ću dobiti je greška u vrijednosti: nevažeći znak za int sa
base ten, I have seven apples. That's just announcing that Python was
bazom 10: 'Imam 7 jabuka'. To je samo najava da Python nije
unable to do the conversion. A motivation for one thing is, this is
mogao uraditi konverziju. Motivacija je u jednu ruku
that, if I call input, say, tell me the number of shoes.
da ako pozovem input tražeći, naprimjer, "Reci mi broj cipela",
And the user types, say, 863 shoes is the number they want.
I korisnik upiše, recimo, 863 je broj cipela koje želim,
I get back a string if my shoe store has only 627 shoes left then I can't right now
dobiću string. Ako je u mojoj prodavnici ostalo samo 627 cipela, ne mogu odmah
compare the string 863 to the number 627. The solution here is to take the result of
uporediti string 863 sa brojem 627. Rješenje je da uzmem rezultat
what the user types and turn it into an int.
upisan od strane korisnika i pretvorim ga u int,
Save it in a variable and now I can do my comparison.
spasim to u varijablu i sada mogu uraditi poređenje.
Are there enough shoes left in order to satisfy my customer?
Da li je ostalo dovoljno cipela kako bih zadovoljio svog kupca?
And the answer is no.
I odgovor je ne.